The eye will receive these light photons at the retina.
L'횇혫il va recevoir ces photons lumineux au niveau de la r횄짤tine.
The light rays first pass through all the layers,
Les rayons lumineux traversent d'abord toutes les couches,
to reach a place called photoreceptors.
pour  arriver  vers  un  lieu  qu 'on  appelle  les  photor횄짤cepteurs.
These photoreceptors are active because they are also in an area
Ces photor횄짤cepteurs sont actifs parce qu'ils sont aussi dans une zone
called the pigmented area.
qu'on appelle la zone pigmentaire.
A pigmented area, first layer here.
Une zone pigmentaire, premi횄짢re couche ici.
Then you have what are called photoreceptors.
Puis vous avez ce qu'on appelle les photor횄짤cepteurs.
which are of two types, called cones and rods,
qui  sont  de  deux  ordres  qu 'on  appelle  les  c횄쨈nes  et  les  b횄짖tonnets
then it will
puis  횄짠a  va
pass through a layer of cells called bipolar cells
traverser vers une couche des cellules qu'on appelle les cellules bipolaires
then it will go to another layer of cells called ganglion cells
puis 횄짠a va aller sur une autre couche des cellules qu'on appelle les cellules
and it is they who will gather all their axons will gather
ganglionaires  et  c 'est  eux  qui  vont  r횄짤unir  tous  leurs  axones  va  se
to gather
r횄짤unir
to form the optic nerve and
pour  former  en  fait  le  nerf  optique  et
therefore transform the trans
transformer  donc  la  trans
Reproduction happens at this level.
La reproduction se fait 횄혻 ce niveau-ci.
Now, if we go a little further, we see photoreceptors.
Maintenant, si on va un petit peu plus loin, on voit des photor횄짤cepteurs.
We see this layer of bipolar cells and ganglion cells.
On voit cette couche des cellules bipolaires et des cellules ganglionnaires.
And we see another new layer of cells called horizontal cells.
Et on voit encore une nouvelle couche de cellules qu'on appelle les cellules horizontales.
We saw them a little bit here.
On les voyait un petit peu ici.
Horizontal cells that allow to capture information
Des cellules horizontales qui permettent de capter les informations
and redistribute it to the bipolar cells first.
et de les redistribuer vers les cellules d'abord bipolaires.
Then below, you still have...
Puis en dessous, vous avez encore...
Another layer, before the ganglion cells, called amacrine cells.
Encore  une  autre  couche,  avant  les  cellules  ganglionaires,  qu 'on  appelle  les  cellules  amacrines.
Again, so as not to lose all the information that would arrive,
De nouveau, pour ne pas perdre toutes les informations qui arriveraient,
it will again gather these cells and redirect them.
횄짠a va de nouveau rassembler ces cellules-l횄혻 et rediriger.
So that gives us quite a lot of information already to capture.
Donc 횄짠a nous fait quand m횄짧me pas mal d'informations d횄짤j횄혻 pour capter.
Let's take the example of a photoreceptor here that has the shape of a cone.
Prenons  l 'exemple  d 'un  photor횄짤cepteur  ici  qui  a  la  forme  d 'un  c횄쨈ne.
And we see that this photoreceptor is made of an outer segment, an
Et  on  voit  que  ce  photor횄짤cepteur  est  fait  d 'un  segment  externe,  d 'un
inner segment.
segment  interne.
a nucleus and a synaptic terminal.
d'un noyau et d'une terminaison synaptique.
In the outer segment, you have what are called plasma membranes
Dans  le  segment  externe,  vous  avez  ce  qu 'on  appelle  des  membranes
membranes
plasmiques
and you have an assembly of small discs.
et vous avez un assemblage de petits disques.
And in these small discs, you have what is called a protein,
Et  dans  ces  petits  disques,  vous  avez  ce  qu 'on  appelle  une  prot횄짤ine,
called opsin.
qu'on appelle l'opsine.
For the rod, this opsin is called rhodopsin
Elle va s'appeler, pour le b횄짖tonnet, cette opsine s'appelle la rhodopsine
and for the cones.
et pour les c횄쨈nes.
Iodopsin.
L'iodopsine.
Now, you imagine, we are at the level of these photoreceptors.
Maintenant, vous imaginez, on est au niveau de ces photor횄짤cepteurs.
We see that at the level of the rods,
Wir sehen, dass an den St채bchen,
there is a small molecule attached to this rhodopsin
es ein kleines Molek체l gibt, das an dieses Rhodopsin gebunden ist,
called retinal.
das Retinal genannt wird.
You have these small stacked discs.
Sie haben diese kleinen gestapelten Scheiben.
We go inside these small discs.
Wir gehen in diese kleinen Scheiben hinein.
We have rhodopsin, it's a protein,
Wir haben Rhodopsin, das ist ein Protein,
to which a molecule called retinal is attached.
an das ein Molek체l gebunden ist, das wir Retinal nennen.
The moment the light hits, it was like this, and it will change shape.
In dem Moment, in dem das Licht auftrifft, war es so, und es wird seine
shape.
Form 채ndern.
It will make a movement like this.
Es wird eine solche Bewegung machen.
This retinal changes shape and transforms rhodopsin into
Dieses Retinal 채ndert seine Form und wandelt das Rhodopsin in
metarhodopsin.
Metarhodopsin um.
And this transformation triggers a succession of chemical cascades at the cellular membrane level.
Und diese Umwandlung l철st auf der Ebene der Zellmembran eine Abfolge von
chemical cascades
chemischen Kaskaden aus,
which will prevent sodium from entering.
die das Eindringen von Natrium verhindern.
Non-permeability of the membrane.
Nicht-Permeabilit채t der Membran.
and this non-permeability of the membrane creates, as we have already seen,
und diese Nicht-Permeabilit채t der Membran erzeugt, wie wir bereits gesehen haben,
simply an ionic change, among others to sodium ions,
einfach eine ionische Ver채nderung, unter anderem bei den Natriumionen,
and it creates a membrane potential that creates a nerve impulse, which
und das erzeugt ein Membranpotential, das einen Nervenimpuls erzeugt, der
changes.
sich 채ndert.
So it's simply an ionic change of the membrane
Es ist also einfach eine ionische Ver채nderung der Membran,
which becomes permeable and non-permeable,
die durchl채ssig und nicht durchl채ssig wird,
and so the impulse changes and creates, as we had already seen, simply
und somit 채ndert sich der Impuls und erzeugt, wie wir bereits gesehen haben, einfach
an impulse.
einen Impuls.
So the light arrives, it passes through all the layers.
Das Licht kommt also an, es durchquert alle Schichten.
I must have what is called a pigment here.
Ich muss das haben, was wir hier ein Pigment nennen.
And this pigment, where do we find it?
Und dieses Pigment, wo finden wir es?
We find ourselves in beta-carotene, in carrots.
Wir finden es im Beta-Carotin, in der Karotte.
It's vitamin A.
Es ist Vitamin A.
Important to activate in this opsin, in
Wichtig, um in diesem Topzin, in
this rhodopsin or in these iodopsins,
diesem Rhodopsin oder in diesen Iodopsinen,
it will activate phenomena.
Ph채nomene zu aktivieren.
You have photoreceptors, the cones.
Sie haben Photorezeptoren, die Zapfen.
Cones or rods will mainly be found in the peripheral retina.
Die Zapfen oder die St채bchen befinden sich haupts채chlich in der peripheren Netzhaut.
This somewhat peripheral vision, there, is a vision that is not very detailed,
Diese etwas periphere Sicht ist eine wenig detaillierte Sicht,
which is, however, sensitive to light and has no color.
die jedoch lichtempfindlich ist und keine Farbe hat.
While cone cells, they give a lot of detail,
W채hrend die Zapfenzellen viele Details liefern,
they are not very sensitive and it gives color and central vision.
sind sie wenig empfindlich und geben die Farbe und das zentrale Sehen.
Cone cells, you have cone cells,
Die Zapfenzellen, Sie haben Zapfenzellen,
For blue, red and green, these are shadow lengths that make
F체r Blau, Rot und Gr체n sind es Schattenl채ngen, die machen
arrive and these are types of opsins that will be found.
ankommen, und das sind Arten von Opsinen, die sich wiederfinden werden.
Now, I'll take it again. The rods. Three parts. Outer segment, inner segment,
Nun, ich wiederhole. Die St채bchen. Drei Teile. Au횩ensegment, Innensegment,
inner segment, synaptic terminal.
synaptische Endigung.
What interests us is the outer segment. The outer segment contains a lot of
Was uns interessiert, ist das Au횩ensegment. Das Au횩ensegment enth채lt eine Menge kleiner
small discs.
Scheiben.
These small discs are called opsin.
Diese kleinen Scheiben nennt man Opsin.
These opsins are called, in the case of rods, rhodopsin,
Diese Opsine hei횩en, im Falle der St채bchen, Rhodopsin,
and in the case of cones, iodopsin.
und im Falle der Zapfen, Iodopsin.
Opsin, the name we will find for rods or for cones.
Opsin, der Name, den wir f체r die St채bchen oder f체r die Zapfen finden werden.
If now we go further, we see that, for example, at the level of the rods, rhodopsin, so
Wenn wir nun weitergehen, sehen wir, dass zum Beispiel bei den St채bchen das Rhodopsin, also
opsin, becomes rhodopsin.
das Opsin, zum Rhodopsin wird.
In this rhodopsin, you have molecules.
In diesem Rhodopsin haben Sie Molek체le.
And these molecules are called retinal, which in fact changes its
Und diese Molek체le nennt man Retinal, das tats채chlich seine
shape and makes this rhodopsin become meta-rhodopsin.
Form 채ndert und bewirkt, dass dieses Rhodopsin zum Meta-Rhodopsin wird.
Changes shape.
횆ndert die Form.
And the change in shape creates a chemical cascade at the
Und die Form채nderung erzeugt eine chemische Kaskade auf
membrane level which causes the polarity of the membrane to change and
Membranebene, die bewirkt, dass sich die Polarit채t der Membran 채ndert und
becomes impermeable.
undurchl채ssig wird.
I can't get in anymore, right?
Ich kann nicht mehr rein, oder?
I'm a sodium ion, you see, it's over, bang, for
Ich bin ein Natrium-Ion, siehst du, es ist vorbei, zack, f체r
a given moment.
einen bestimmten Moment.
And then after, I can, and it makes a membrane change
Und dann kann ich wieder, und das bewirkt eine Membranver채nderung,
that creates the electric current.
die den elektrischen Strom erzeugt.
And it's always like that.
Und so ist es die ganze Zeit.
And so, it's just a molecular cascade, and it's even more, it's an ionic cascade
Und so ist es nur eine molekulare Kaskade, und es ist sogar mehr, es ist eine ionische
of sodium ions, you see.
Kaskade von Natrium-Ionen, siehst du.
I can, I can't anymore.
Ich kann, ich kann nicht mehr.
I can, I can't anymore, I can, I can't anymore.
Ich kann, ich kann nicht mehr, ich kann, ich kann nicht mehr.
I can, I can't anymore, so...
Ich kann, ich kann nicht mehr, bewirkt, dass...
I'm moving forward.
Ich gehe voran.
And that creates the impulse.
Und das erzeugt den Impuls.
That's how I get this transduction.
So habe ich diese Transduktion.
Do you understand?
Verstehst du?
The transmission of light energy takes place in the photoreceptors.
Die 횥bertragung der Lichtenergie findet in den Photorezeptoren statt.
So it starts with the absorption of what?
Also beginnt es mit der Absorption von was?
Of photons.
Von Photonen.
It will create the variation of the photoreceptor membrane.
Das wird die Variation der Membran der Photorezeptoren erzeugen.
By a sensitive pigment, opsin.
Durch ein empfindliches Pigment, das Opsin.
It is called rhodopsin or iodopsin, depending on whether we are on cones
Man nennt es Rhodopsin oder Iodopsin, je nachdem, ob man sich auf den Zapfen
or rods.
oder den St채bchen befindet.
And so, they are located on small discs in
Und  sie  befinden  sich  auf  kleinen  Scheiben  im
the outer segment of the rod.
채u횩eren  Segment  des  St채bchens.
Now, we go in with the microscope.
Jetzt gehen wir mit dem Mikroskop hinein.
We go into these small discs.
Wir gehen in diese kleinen Scheiben hinein.
When the light arrives and touches, it changes shape, which
Wenn  das  Licht  ankommt  und  ber체hrt,  채ndert  es  seine  Form,  was
which causes a chemical cascade.
eine  chemische  Kaskade  ausl철st.
It is linked to rhodopsin, because there is a conformational change of
Das  h채ngt  mit  Rhodopsin  zusammen,  weil  es  eine  Konformations채nderung
a molecule called retinal, which will
eines  Molek체ls  gibt,  das  man  Retinal  nennt,  das
trigger this transduction phenomenon because it will change the shape of the retinal, which
dieses  Transduktionsph채nomen  ausl철sen  wird,  weil  es  die  Form  des  Retinals  채ndern  wird,  das
absorbs light and allows rhodopsin to turn into metarhodopsin, which makes
Licht  absorbiert  und  es  erm철glicht,  Rhodopsin  in  Metarhodopsin  umzuwandeln,  was
the membrane, this plasma membrane here.
die  Membran,  diese  Plasmamembran  hier,  macht.
Less permeable to sodium, we can no longer enter, which in fact creates a change
Weniger  permeabel  f체r  Natrium,  wir  k철nnen  nicht  mehr  eintreten,  was  tats채chlich  eine  횆nderung
in permeability, which will modify the membrane potential
der  Permeabilit채t  erzeugt,  was  das  Membranpotential  ver채ndern  wird
and which will allow the emission of a nerve impulse to the next cell.
und  was  die  Aussendung  eines  Nervenimpulses  bis  zur  n채chsten  Zelle  erm철glichen  wird.
And it's the same pattern. And that's where we have the importance of vitamin
Und  es  ist  dasselbe  Schema.  Und  hier  liegt  die  Bedeutung  von
A, because it is necessary for the synthesis of retinal
Vitamin  A,  weil  es  f체r  die  Synthese  von  Retinal  notwendig  ist,
of this molecule to manufacture...
dieses  Molek체ls,  um  herzustellen...
This molecule, I need vitamin A and if I have a vitamin A deficiency,
F체r  dieses  Molek체l  brauche  ich  Vitamin  A,  und  wenn  ich  einen  Vitamin-A-Mangel
A, I will actually have a loss of sight, especially
habe,  werde  ich  tats채chlich  einen  Sehverlust  haben,  besonders
at night.
nachts.